[Music]
the salting and pickling of fish
produces a novel dna mutating chemical
called cmba which is formed from a
reaction of the salt nitrite
preservatives and methionine an amino
acid found concentrated in animal
proteins
the nitrites can also interact with
other protein components to form nitroso
compounds a powerful class of
carcinogens found in cigarette smoke
this may explain why processed meats
such as bacon ham hot dogs lunch meat
sausage have been tied to increase
stomach cancer risk but this extends to
fresh unprocessed unsalted meat as well
but wait i thought most stomach cancer
was caused by an infection with a
stomach bacteria called h pylori
there's a synergistic interaction
between h pylori-induced inflammation
gastritis and diet in the formation of
stomach cancer check it out researchers
in china discovered that even in
genetically vulnerable individuals
infected with a particular pathogenic
strain of h pylori did not appear to be
at increased risk of stomach cancer
unless
they ate about an ounce or more of pork
per day
an average pork chop is like six ounces
this is a striking example of how our
diet can sometimes trump both our genes
and environmental influences like
cancer-causing infections
but is there a way to wipe out the h
pylori in the first place
normally you'd use a triple antibiotic
cocktail of drugs to kill off h pylori
but patient compliance is difficult to
maintain to the quantity of drugs taken
and the adverse side effects
anything we can eat to wipe them out
instead
decades before the detoxifying and
anti-cancer abilities were discovered
sulforaphane that remarkable compound in
cruciferous vegetables was originally
described for its anti-microbial
activity
after hearing anecdotal reports of
individuals with h pylori-induced peptic
ulcer disease experiencing dramatic and
sometimes unexpected relief after eating
three-day-old broccoli sprouts
researchers at johns hopkins university
and elsewhere decided to put broccoli
sprouts to the test
not only did broccoli sprout extracts
kill antibiotic resistant restrains of h
pylori in a petri dish some patients who
were given as little as a third of a cup
of broccoli sprouts a day for a week
were able to eradicate their h pylori
infection
so how about a randomized controlled
trial broccoli sprouts versus alfalfa
sprouts
and
those given two to three servings of
broccoli a day worth of sprouts were
able to significantly cut down on
markers of both h pylori colonization
and stomach lining inflammation
the broccoli sprouts may be able to
eradicate h pylori in the majority of
patients 56 percent
the standard triple drug antibiotic
therapy is much more effective about 90
percent eradication still for those who
don't meet the criteria for drug
treatment cruciferous vegetables may
present a safe natural way to combat h
pylori in the development of stomach
cancer
a compilation of 22 population studies
found that eating more cruciferous
vegetables was associated with a
significantly lower stomach cancer risk
but broccoli has never been directly put
to the test
but garlic has
observational studies dating back to the
1960s on japanese migrants have
suggested that allium family vegetables
garlic and onion family vegetables may
be protective against stomach cancer to
date there have been dozens of such
studies published and overall eating
lots of alien vegetables was indeed
associated with significantly lower
stomach cancer risk
there's evidence of publication bias
though meaning there appears to have
been other studies that maybe failed to
show such an effect that were shelved
and never published
even if this weren't the case
observational studies can never prove
cause and effect
maybe low garlic and onion consumption
didn't contribute to stomach cancer for
example but rather stomach cancer
contributed to low garlic and onion
consumption
decades of h pylori stomach inflammation
leading up to the cancer may have led to
individuals choosing bland diets to
avoid discomfort you can't know if
garlic really helps
uh until you put it to the test
louis pasteur
was evidently the first to describe the
antibacterial effect of onion and garlic
juices petri dish studies have shown
that garlic is effective in suppressing
the growth of h pylori at concentrations
achievable in the stomach with a single
clove even some antibiotic resistant
strains are susceptible but does this
translate into stopping the growth of
cancer a randomized double-blind
controlled trial was launched to find
out
thousands of individuals at high risk
for stomach cancer from 13 villages in
china were randomized into various
combinations of antibiotics garlic
supplements and
supplements
and just a few weeks of antibiotics led
to a significant decrease in subsequent
pre-cancerous stomach growth seven years
later and a significant decrease in
subsequent stomach cancer by 15 years
what about the garlic
no benefit by seven years
and only a non-statistically significant
reduction after 15 years
but
in 2019 we got the 22-year update 15
years after the study ended and
those who had taken the garlic did
indeed have a significantly lower risk
of subsequently dying from cancer
though interestingly the protective
effect of garlic only seemed to manifest
among non-drinkers
[Music]
you